Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Edward Lear miscellaneous drawings, 1849-1866 (MS Typ 55.14): Guide.
Edward Lear miscellaneous drawings,
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The table and the chair: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (160); 1s.(2p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The table and the chair and Calico pie: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (161); 1s.(1p.)
  Two nonsense poems.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The Yonghy-Bonghy-Bò: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (162); 1s.(4p.)
  - Page 1
  - Page 2-3
  - Page 4
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The Yonghy-Bonghy-Bò: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (163); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The Yonghy-Bonghy-Bò: manuscript (by copyist); [no place, undated]., (164); 1s.(1p.)
  Music only, with manuscript note in Lear's autograph.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. [The courtship of the Yonghy-Bonghy-Bò]: uncorrected page-proof of Lear's musical setting for the poem; [no place, undated]., (165); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man on the Humber: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (166); 1s.(1p.)
  Nonsense verse with drawing. Matted.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. With all my heart, then let us part: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (167); 1s.(1p.)
  A serious poem.
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. 10 photographic reproductions of manuscripts and drawings in the W. B. O. Field-Harvard collection., (168)
  [8 photographs present as of 1995 February 15].
  *42M-236 & 243. Gift of W.B.O.Field, 27 Jul 1942.
  - Photograph 1
  - Photograph 2
  - Photograph 3
  - Photograph 4
  - Photograph 5
  - Photograph 6
  - Photograph 7
  - Photograph 8
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. [Portrait photograph]. Mounted with 1 small rebus drawn by Lear, and 1 autograph visiting card., (169)
  *42M-225F. Gift of Philip Hofer, 27 Jul 1942.
  - Complete item
  - Photograph
  - Newsclipping, recto
  - Newsclipping, verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old Man of the Dee: drawing., (170); 1s.(1p.)
  Probably gift of Philip Hofer; removed from unprocessed collection material left behind by Houghton Librarian Carolyn Jakeman.